NITHIN RAJIDI

E-Mail: nithinreddyr@gmail.com | Phone: +91 8686415134 | Microsoft Certified: PL-300 (Power BI Data Analyst) & Al-102 (Azure Al Engineer) | Location: Hyderabad, India

SUMMARY

IT professional with 11+ years of experience across Azure, Power BI, ADF, Synapse, relational databases, and MSBI. Architected Analytical solutions for customers across various industries.

Strong at BI development, cloud/data migrations, performance tuning, and stakeholder collaboration. Oversaw and led vendor teams, ensuring successful completion of projects by coordinating efforts, monitoring progress, and maintaining clear communication between all stakeholders.

Active contributor to the Microsoft Fabric community.

CERTIFICATIONS & COMMUNITY

- PL-300: Microsoft Certified Power BI Data Analyst Associate
- AI-102: Microsoft Certified: Azure AI Engineer Associate
- Fabric Community Profile
- Stakeholder Management

EXPERIENCE

Microsoft India — Consultant (Jun 2021 – Present)

- Designed analytical solutions for clients across various industries.
- Lead the vendor teams overlooking end-to-end project completions.
- Built Power BI reports on Synapse SQL pools for education-sector clients.
- Utilized DevOps APIs to automate project management reports in Power BI for multiple projects.
- Built Power BI reports for Sales consolidation for gaming sector clients utilizing data from blob storage.
- Built Data model and Paginated reports for Government sector customer.
- Developed Azure Data Factory (ADF) pipelines and dataflows.
- Migrated Tableau reports to Power BI with robust data modeling (Oracle Data source).
- Automated Migration of Power BI tenant to tenant Migrations for a customer utilizing API's and PowerShell scripts.
- Built NLP Solutions for IT Service Desk for a Service based customer.

- Built AI Solutions for Pharma and Financial Solution Customers.
- Coordinated large-scale migration projects from on-premises to Azure for banking and health care clients.

Wells Fargo — Application Systems Engineer (Sep 2016 – Jun 2021)

- Managed a team of six in overseeing application support and development initiatives.
- Delivered SSIS/SSRS/Power BI solutions; Migrated legacy workloads and standardized models and measures for consistency and reuse.
- Performed SQL performance tuning (indexes, plans, DMVs) and implemented HA/DR patterns; stabilized critical reporting workloads.
- Drove incident response and root-cause analysis for data quality and performance issues; implemented preventive controls and monitoring.
- Planned and executed side-by-side database/report migrations with zero data-loss;
 coordinated UAT and production cutovers.

IBM India Pvt Ltd — SQL Database Administrator & Developer (May 2014 – Sep 2016)

- Built and maintained database solutions and ETL (DTS/SSIS); supported production operations.
- Analyzed/optimized T-SQL and ETL performance; implemented fixes with minimal downtime.
 - Worked with SSRS (migrations $2000/2005 \rightarrow 2008$ R2), configured data sources and security.
- Managed backups/restores, recovery models, maintenance plans, logins/roles, and auditing (SOX).

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Databases: Azure SQL Managed Instance, Azure SQL Database, Microsoft SQL Server

BI/ETL/Reporting: Power BI, SSIS, SSRS, ADF, Synapse, Fabric

Languages/Scripting: T-SQL, Python, PowerShell

Tools: SSMS, BIDS/SSDT, Report Builder, Visual Studio, DMA, Tabular Editor, DAX Studio

Domains: Banking, Capital Markets, Telecommunications, Education, Pharma, Gaming

AWARDS

- Industry Solution Award Microsoft
- Customer Champion Wells Fargo (Q3 2018–19).
- Customer Champion award winner.

EDUCATION

- B.Tech, Electronics & Communication Engineering JNTU Institute of Engineering, Hyderabad (2013)
- Executive Post Graduation Programme in AI & ML IIIT Bangalore